Guide to the Administrative Papers of President John Crittenden Sawhill 1974-1981 (Bulk 1975-1979) RG.3.0.8
New York University Archives
- Series IX: Public Relations
  - Intellectual Life in NY (the Future of); Invitations and Follow-up, Mar 1978-Apr 1979 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Science and Society; Correspondence, Apr 1978-Jul 1979 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Science and Society; Dinners, Jan 1978-Mar 1978 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Science and Society; Dinners, May 1978-Sep 1978 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Society of Fellows, Feb 1977-Jul 1977 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Society of Fellows, Sep 1977-Aug 1978 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Society of Fellows, Nov 1978-Sep 1980 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Intellectual Life in NY; Society of Fellows; Dinners, Jun 1977-Oct 1980 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Invitations; Outside; (A-AL), undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Am), undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Invitations; Outside; (An-Az), undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Invitations; Outside; (B), undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Ca-Ch), undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Ci-Cl), undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Co-Cu), undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Invitations; Outside; (D), undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Invitations; Outside; (E), undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Invitations; Outside; (F), undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Invitations; Outside; (G-H), undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Invitations; Outside; (I-J), undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Invitations; Outside; (K-L), undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Invitations; Outside; (M), undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Na), undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Invitations; Outside; (Ne-Ni), undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Invitations; Outside; (O-P), undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Invitations; Outside; (R), undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Invitations; Outside; (S), undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Invitations; Outside; (T), undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Invitations; Outside; (U-V), undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Invitations; Outside; (W), undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Invitations; Outside; (X-Z), undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Invitations; Outside; (New York City), undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Invitations; NYU; (A-B), undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Invitations; NYU; (C-D), undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Invitations; NYU; (E), undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Invitations; NYU; (F), undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Invitations; NYU; (G-L), undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Invitations; NYU; (M), undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Invitations; NYU; (N-P), undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Invitations; NYU; (R-Z), undated (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Public Occasions; Commencement, Feb 1976-Jul 1976 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Public Occasions; Commencement, Nov 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Public Occasions; Commencement, Jan 1978-Jun 1979 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Public Occasions; Commencement, Sep 1979-Jul 1980 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Public Occasions; Conferences, Aug 1975-Jan 1978 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Public Occasions; Conferences; General Education Conference, Apr 1977-Jul 1977 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Public Occasions; Convocations, Jan 1976-Apr 1977 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Public Occasions; Convocations, Feb 1978-May 1980 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Public Occasions; Convocations; Special Convocation for H.E. William R. Tolbert Jr., President of the Republic of Liberia, Aug 1976-Sep 1976 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Public Occasions; Convocations; Special Convocation for H.E. William R. Tolbert Jr., President of the Republic of Liberia, Sep 1976-Nov 1976 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Public Occasions; Dedications, Apr 1975-Dec 1979 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Sep 1975 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Oct 1975-May 1976 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jun 1976 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Oct 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Sep 1977-Nov 1977 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Dec 1977 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jan 1978-Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, May 1978-Jun 1978 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jul 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Sep 1978 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Oct 1978 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Nov 1978 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Dec 1978 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jan 1979 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Feb 1979 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Mar 1979 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Apr 1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, May 1979 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jun 1979 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jul 1979 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Aug 1979-Oct 1979 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Nov 1979 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Dec 1979 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Jan 1980-Feb 1980 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Mar 1980-Apr 1980 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, May 1980-Jun 1980 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons, Oct 1980-Mar 1981 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; John Brademas, Jun 1979 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; George H. W. Bush, Mar 1979 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; John C. Danforth, Nov 1978 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; Peter Drucker, Apr 1979 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture, Nov 1979 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Public Occasions; Lectures and/or Receptions, Dinners, Luncheons; Second Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture, Nov 1980 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Pre-NYU, Feb 1974-Jan 1975 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks, Feb 1975 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks, Mar 1975 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Pre-NYU, Apr 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Pre-NYU, Apr 1975 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Pre-NYU, May 1975-Jun 1975 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Pre-NYU, Jul 1975-Aug 1975 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, May 1975-Sep 1975 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Sep 1975 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Oct 1975 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Oct 1975 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Nov 1975 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Dec 1975 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jan 1976-Feb 1976 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Mar 1976 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Apr 1976 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, May 1976 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, May 1976 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jun 1976 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jul 1976-Sep 1976 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Oct 1976 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Nov 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jan 1977-Mar 1977 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Apr 1977-May 1977 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jun 1977 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Sep 1977 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Oct 1977-Nov 1977 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Dec 1977-Mar 1978 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Apr 1978 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, May 1978 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jun 1978 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Aug 1978-Sep 1978 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Oct 1978 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Nov 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jan 1979-Feb 1979 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Feb 1979 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Mar 1979-Apr 1979 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, May 1979 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jun 1979 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Jul 1979-Aug 1979 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Sep 1979 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; NYU, NYC, Education, Sep 1979-May 1980 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Aug 1975-Sep 1975 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Oct 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Dec 1975-Jan 1976 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Feb 1976-Mar 1976 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Apr 1976-May 1976 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Jun 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Sep 1976-Oct 1976 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Nov 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Jan 1977 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Feb 1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Mar 1977-Apr 1977 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, May 1977-Sep 1977 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Oct 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Jan 1978-Mar 1978 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, May 1978-Oct 1978 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Nov 1978 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Dec 1978 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Jan 1979-Mar 1979 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Apr 1979 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, May 1979-Jun 1979 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Energy, Economy, etc, Jun 1979-Oct 1979 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Background Materials, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, May 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jan 1976-May 1976 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jun 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jan 1977-May 1977 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jun 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Sep 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jan 1978-May 1978 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jun 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Sep 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jan 1979-May 1979 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Jun 1979-Aug 1979 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Miscellaneous Correspondence, Sep 1979-Apr 1981 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Speakers Bureaus, American Program Bureau, Nov 1974-Sep 1979 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Speakers Bureaus, Harry Walker, Inc, Feb 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Public Presentations, Speeches and/or Articles, Interviews, Remarks; Speakers Bureaus, Miscellaneous, Feb 1975-Jul 1979 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Publications, Sep 1975-Oct 1979 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Publications; Acknowledgments, Sep 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Publications; Acknowledgments, Sep 1976-Jul 1980 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Publications; NYU Press, Oct 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Publications; NYU Press, Sep 1976-Jul 1980 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Publications; Newspapers; Student, Feb 1978-Mar 1980 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Publications; Non-NYU, Jul 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, Jun 1978-Feb 1980 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Requests; Miscellaneous, Aug 1975-Sep 1980 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Special Projects, Jun 1978 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, Listings (Sawhill), Sep 1975-Aug 1978 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Visits/Visitors, Jun 1975-Dec 1976 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Visits/Visitors, Jan 1977-Feb 1980 (Box 61, Folder 13)
- Series X: Schools and Divisions
  This series, second largest in the collection, is contained in 14.5 Hollinger boxes measuring 7 linear feet. Its subject matter is the academic business of the University. There are sequences for all of the schools in operation in the pertinent years, including, where extant, holdings for departments and divisions within them. An attempt has been made to describe each major sequence consistently, incorporating, when present, files labeled Accreditation, Advisory Council, Budget & Financial Matters, Faculty Meeting Minutes and Search for Dean. This collection contains only listings of minutes by school and date. Actual Faculty Meeting minutes have been transferred to relevant Record Groups. Some materials cover divisions reporting to the Central Administration. The schools are placed in the order consistent with Archives practice, from Arts and Science through School of the Arts. Faculty of Arts and Science (FAS) departmental and divisional matters are located following the records of the several connected administrative units; non-FAS units follow those of the School of the Arts. Documents concerned with individual personnel matters were discarded.
  FAS materials occupy Box 62 through the first third of Box 65. A major development effort, reflective of the centrality of the Arts and Sciences at NYU, was in the planning stage. An outline of FAS development priorities proposed by Dean Norman Cantor is in Box 62, folder 5, n.d. In folder 6 NYU officers evaluate a revised FAS plan, 7/31/79. For an example of Norman Cantor's personal style, see Cantor to Sawhill 10/16/78. Succeeding folders contain routine material generated in the administrative units Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS), Box 62,folders 15-17, and Box 63, folders 1-2, Washington Square and University College (WSUC), folders 3-4. Divisional and departmental matters follow, led by Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, folders 5-8 and Institute of Fine Arts (IFA), folders 9-15. Some units within FAS experienced marked turmoil in this period, for Anthropology Department see Box 64, folder 1, and Biology Department, folders 4-7.
  Business Schools material reflects local and institutional interest in advancing the schools' reputation. It begins with the undergraduate School of Business and Public Administration (BPA), Box 65, folder 7. Graduate School of Business Administration (GBA) matters appear initially in folder 11 and continue through the first half of Box 66. In Box 65, folder 13, NYU confronts City University of New York (CUNY) expansion plans for Baruch College. Also in folder 13, GBA is ranked #2 in numbers of business executives with NYU degrees. In folder 15, humanities Ph.D.s switch to business. Dean William Dill's 78-79 Report to the GBA faculty appears in folder 16, while folder 17 offers some thoughts on how to upgrade NYU's reputation and ranking, Fred Siegel to Sawhill 10/5/78 and Sawhill to Siegel 10/16/78. A GBA draft Development Plan is also placed in folder 17, followed, in Box 66, folder 1, by a revised version by Sylvia Baruch, 3/7/79. This in turn is followed by a Dill commentary on the Baruch version, 3/8/79. Then, in folder 2, another kind of plan appears, created by a faculty committee and titled "Strategy for GBA," 6/1/79.
  The focal point for the School of Continuing Education (SCE) at this time is another presidential management initiative, in this instance a proposed reorganization of SCE, 11/3/75, Box 67, folder 3. Extensive proposal-related correspondence occupies folders 4-10. Routine matters, mainly program-related, precede and succeed consideration of the proposed reorganization scheme, in Box 66, folders 7-12 and Box 67, folders 11-13.
  College of Dentistry records of this period are located in Box 68, folders 1-8. This unit was in considerable turmoil, experiencing both a fiscal crisis and an unexpected decanal resignation. For particulars of the former see the several versions of the New York State Education Department (NYSED) "Report on Financing of Independent Dental Schools," with a draft in Box 68, folder 2, 8/19/77, along with Sawhill's comments to Commissioner of Education Gordon Ambach 9/7/77, folder 3. NYU's responses, along with others' comments, were incorporated in the final version, distributed by Ambach to "members of the Board of Regents," 9/28/77, folder 3. Folder 3 also documents the "sudden and unexpected" change in the unit's leadership with the resignation of Dean Donald Giddon, as cited by Acting Dean Richard Mumma in his 1/4/78 Statement to the Faculty. See the Borowitz Papers, Boxes 66 and 67, for some prior history of Dentistry's financial problems.
  School of Education content is for the most part routine, concerned with matters such as course development and approval, budget control, faculty recruitment, etc., Box 68, folders 9-13 and Box 69, folders 1-7. The nature of the Education faculty's philosophy may be gleaned in its mission statement of 3/29/76, which opens by both "reaffirm(ing) its traditional professional purpose and, in keeping with modern concerns, broaden(ing) and sharpen(ing) its purview" Box 68, folder 10.